panopta.com 2009-06-20

# Privacy Policy | Panopta

### About Panopta

## Panopta Newsletter

Subscribe to our email newsletter to get the latest news about what's happening at Panopta. 

Your address will _only_ be used for the newsletter, and will never be sold or used for other marketing purposes.

At Panopta, we take your privacy and the security of the information you share with us very seriously. If you have any questions about the policy or how it applies to your data, please contact us at [privacy@panopta.com](mailto:privacy@panopta.com).

## Data Collected

When you visit our public website, we collect the URL from which you linked to our site, your IP address, and your browser type and version. This information is collected anonymously and is not linked to your personal information. We collect email addresses from visitors to our site that wish to opt into our monthly email newsletter. 

If you create a trial account, we will collect basic customer information, limited to the minimum data necessary to create a trial account. Upon upgrading to a full paying account, we will gather full contact and payment information in order to collect payment for our services as agreed to by the customer. 

We use cookies for session tracking in both the public website and control panel. No personally identifiable information is stored in the cookie data. 

## Use of Customer Information

The information we collect from our public website is used in aggregate form to improve the content of our website and guide our advertising and marketing practices. Individual visitor session data is never used for this purpose. Any contact information given in the process of signing up for a trial account or mailing list will only be used internally and never sold or shared with a third party for marketing purposes. Opt-out instructions are included in all communication so that you can remove yourself from future communication whenever you would like. 

Customer contact and billing information is only used to provide service and collect payment for our montoring and outage management services. It is never shared with third parties for marketing purposes, and is only released outside the company to credit card clearing houses, banking institutions, and other similarly situated third parties as required to accomplish the transaction, and as required by law enforcement agencies. Information about the specifics of your monitoring service will not be exposed publicly by Panopta except as an aggregate statistic across our entire customer base. 

In the future, we may use customer information for new uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our privacy policy change we will contact you before we use your data and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. We will also post the policy changes to our website. 

We have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected.
